I'm a show.
And if you need to do that, you can put that on the potty body.
Okay.
So we're gonna do something with picture reading because this can be you can think about
pictures.
It can unscramble that and distract us some.
Alright.
Would you like to look at ten apps.
These are Christmas y photos.
So if you're like, I don't do Christmas, then take this one.
This is more.
You can always do Christmas there.
These two are Santa in them.
So do you have a picture you like to look at?
I don't know if you're a big celebrator Christmas or not.
Xmas.
Yeah.
I know you're not religious.
I'm so blessed.
Express.
Hey.
Do wanna do this one?
This one?
Or this this is one, two, or three?
Which one would y'all do?
You're in a three.
Okay.
Let's do this one.
So this is only a Christmas scene because of oh, I guess, a a couple aspects, but it doesn't
really Mhmm.
It's more of a winter scene than Christmas scene, so it's so it's nice that way.
So let's start with We do open presents at Christmas.
Open presents.
Okay.
So you still celebrate Christmas.
You're just personally not a believer in God.
That's it's fascinating to me.
I'm not paying you that.
No.
I hate that.
Are you guys religious at all of the family or just Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
So you're just Everything.
You're you're you're the one who's saying you're sure.
Okay.
So here we go.
Let's take a look at this right here.
The first task is gonna sound simple because you could ask them, do y'all do this?
But the goal of this is just to work on you being able to scan with more ease.
K?
And then start noticing other details.
Even I benefit from this activity.
Even though I can scan the environment, I benefit from this activity too.
So it's something we can all work on.
So the identification is due to working on scanning also what you're seeing.
So I'm noticing, first off, is this dog here.
K?
What are you noticing in this picture here?
Oh, how long was my x?
G then, I and n.
Let's just say G I then s r and l.
So square that.
G lift, I lift, bar max l.
And just kinda make sure you pull back a little bit more, and that will help.
Let's go into a session, actually.
So you have a drill.
Yes.
Back in a couple of drills in there.
Let me mix it all back.
K?
I am noticing the string going through.
What are you noticing?
You're noticing a Push it through.
H then o and m then.
Okay.
X hat.
X hat now?
It's okay.
X hat.
E.
Home.
Good.
X hat.
K.
I am able to see these two robins.
They're curious to me.
These birds.
K.
What are you noticing?
For your dad's video, he should know what you're looking at.
K.
You're gonna see the Context.
Context and the what?
No.
Go for it.
Look right here.
What do you see?
No.
You're the m then, o then, n.
The moon.
Two double taps on that moon.
Yeah.
The moon's a full moon up there.
It's pretty bright.
I actually love it when I come home from my workshop.
In the evening, I fly home, and it is snowing outside or snowed.
Not snowing.
It snowed.
I like to walk out at midnight because it's, like, bright.
So because it's the reflection of the moon on the the snow makes it bright.
So it's still dark outside, but you can see everything, which is really peaceful because
everyone's sleeping while you're there.
So that's kinda it's kinda a cool time.
So this is a scene that we can see.
It's kind of more a nighttime zoom scene due to the fact that you have this moon up.
So we're evening scene.
Blustery day.
K.
But not then I actually have lights on in the house.
So k.
What else?
I was gonna say other things too.
We're gonna say what?
V then?
O and y as in boy for sure.
K.
Number of boys.
Sometimes it's hard to see exactly which gender they are.
K.
I am noticing that What's inside?
The the lights on the tree, which is what one of the things that lets you know that this is a
Christmas Eve.
Yeah.
So what else do you see?
You see a s then with your ice cube then u.
S q u.
Uh-huh.
Cream and.
Then.
That's a r.
Get rid of that.
But a.
A then r then e squall You got a square.
Can you point out I guess that's just mini squares.
Let me see.
I am noticing the light over here in the bushes.
I'm wondering why it's there.
It's it's a lamppost or something else.
K.
So it kinda looks for different things.
Oh, it's see?
No.
That's very cozy.
Good point.
Now we're gonna take this, and we're gonna craft them into sentences.
We're gonna look our sentences.
So let's use this word.
This is sentence structure.
Going.
I'm gonna have you spell a couple of keywords first to kinda warm you a bit more.
Let's go ahead and spell the word snow.
Need you.
Know.
A o one.
S n then o n w.
So W next, I n g e and r.
One child.
Forest.
Forest, f o r e s n t.
I have them.
K.
So Forest.
So doing a sentences here.
Let's use the word dog.
And if you're saying winter, let's do winter in a sentence.
One child.
Prob this thing.
Wincher.
Is she out?
W I n t e r, winter.
Next word.
Enter.
Move your eyes.
V then.
S.
R then.
Move your eyes.
So v then.
R.
I and n, then move your eyes.
Will be m.
S and there's a g there.
So there's a s there.
Right?
Did you want the word brings?
Okay.
Yes.
Did or no?
Rincher brings it's really clean.
Rincher brings s next, m next.
Careful.
A and l brings small.
And the two l's.
Small reaching out.
I and n.
I n.
Move your eyes.
C h then e and s.
Inches.
One hour.
Winter brings small inches.
Go ahead.
O.
Move your eyes.
Go all the there.
Do what makes sense.
Of.
So let's practice the o to the s so that's not having a g in it.
Yeah.
F r.
O, which is crossed.
F of s then I.
Okay.
N o, n with your eyes, shift w.
Small inches of snow.
Watch.
Wanna see you.
You get that that dog in there.
Zipper.
Bring small inches of snow.
See?
And Zipper.
Did you know?
D then o.
Zippers.
Mhmm.
G Zippers.
Zippers.
Into the snows to dogs.
Great.
Nice.
K.
Good reading, honey.
You're good.
Yeah.
Let's go ahead and calm your knees all down like that.
Same first.
You got dog first.
Now let's go ahead and do the words zippers.
Home and lights in a sentence.
Zippers.
Zip zippers.
You can all zip your code if you need to.
It's a little bit chillier, I think, in this office.
K.
Hold in line.
Let's get those in a sentence.
There.
If you wanted to.
See bras.
C.
Move your ice.
A.
N.
Can.
Q and.
Hide it.
Open your eyes.
U.
Q u I then e and t.
Quiet.
Zippers.
Again, quiet.
S, then m.
Move your i's.
I'll lift your vowels up to a vowel.
A l l.
And quiet, small.
It should hit that l twice instead of kinda shifting off it.
K.
Quiet small.
H next.
O next.
H o m next, e next, s.
I have quiet small homes.
Last.
Most spelled.
Spelling.
Good.
H next.
Move your eyes.
Eyes.
H.
Good.
Move your eyes.
Yeah.
H and find it.
A and b.
M.
Good.
And the o.
Have m o r.
Just e.
Half more.
Good.
Then q and u.
In quite small homes have more q u.
Okay.
I e t.
You're making orc, which is okay for these sentences.
And small homes for the small homes, have more quiet.
You gotta get that letter in.
L good, I good, g h d s.
They have lights, more quiet lights.
We need do question one.
That works.
K.
Now let's put the the word mood in this picture into a sentence.
And then we're gonna take a break from the picture for a second and do the skill workout that
can help you at home.
K.
With the it, you can say h o m oops.
I'll do it right this way.
H o m e e.
Just got that j on the way up there.
Home I s is next letter?
U, move your eyes.
People.
N, because u n is umbrella.
It will make sense for umpire.
Is u n, then move your eyes.
Try again.
I or d.
D then e and r.
Home is under t.
Good.
Keep your hand moving.
And then t.
You gotta shift your eyes.
It's under t, then h and e the these are some soft thoughts that are awaiting your mind, and it's
hard to stay focused.
It's under the After lunch or after spelling.
Let's try it m o and o then.
And home is under the moon.
I like that.
So that's what's happening there.
After spelling, we'll go to home to the home store.
Right?
Raise your hand.
Raise your hand and put it out there.
Get So here we go.
What we're gonna do is go like this.
No problem.
K.
I'm gonna cut up some of these rows.
The budget of this is we're just gonna work on making words.
So it builds your skills with your eye movement on the letter board.
It's open ended, but there's no the only thing you gotta do is is one, make words, can be any
word, and two, use at least one letter on top and one on the bottom to work on stretching up and
down.
K?
So with people, you can do this this skill.
So we're gonna take turns.
My turn.
So for instance, you can't spell bad because bad's only on this row, or you can't spell rust
because it's only down here.
You're not gonna fix them.
So I can start with b r, put it down here, a b e.
So I'm gonna be brave.
K?
Your turn.
Spell the word using both rows.
C r e and s t, rest.
Cool.
R e s t, rest.
Uter.
C then what's that?
C then move your eyes.
A and r, Carr.
C a r t s, Carts.
Alright.
Uter.
I'll spell.
S and p e y, spay.
S p e, spay.
They they figure that.
You got you got you can do something with that.
The s p e.
S p then a and d.
What letter are you missing?
It's gonna be s and find it.
P r.
There we go.
E then shout.
Right.
Almost there.
A and d.
Spread.
Good.
My turn.
I'm gonna do the words w a s was.
Your turn.
A then.
Come come to it.
R.
Come to it.
T.
Okay.
There we go.
Art.
My turn.
T e a t.
Your turn.
Thank thank thank Hayden, r and e r.
Good.
My turn.
Let's do s t a r t s starts.
Your turn.
P e s t, best.
My turn.
P e s t, pest.
Your turn.
R e s t.
I got rest, sadly.
Already did.
P r e s and Press it.
Press it twice.
Press.
My turn.
D r e w, Drew.
Your turn.
V.
Stop.
These are e s t.
Vast.
That works.
V e r y, very.
Near term.
There's hundreds of words there, so we're only going to go for so long.
Okay.
R then?
Yep.
Okay.
R then a and p.
R.
There you go.
S t r.
Let's see.
A b.
Strong.
Will turn.
T then, r then up top.
A and b.
Jump.
That's good enough.
So This could be a way to work with your scalp, and then, like, maybe tomorrow with your dad
or Ali, you can do this.
And then you do this side, or you could do this one, or you could do this roll cover and that roll
cover or something.
So you can cover up different letters and find their combinations to build that open ended
without there being any pressure on this just to make sure it's an actual word, and you're in
good shape.
So it didn't work.
Well done.
Now we go on back to our picture.
There.
First.
So now we're gonna ask questions.
General and specific.
While we're working on this question asking is because when you are advocating for yourself in
society and the environment, it's important that you're able to know what to ask to get
information you need.
So if you go to a doctor, your dad or mom may be able to ask some questions.
But what if you have one?
Or if you're having a certain need that you haven't been able to express very well, knowing a
question, you could ask with how you get that need met.
So so then you also creativity is formed from people who are this prince.
First, ask questions.
What's up?
I'm the prince.
Like space travel.
Space travel.
What is that?
Is it possible?
People wrote stories.
Then the scientists came along and asked more questions.
And how can you actually make it happen that it happened?
So if people didn't ask questions, there wouldn't be creativity.
There wouldn't be science.
So that's what we're working on.
This is very important.
You know how to ask questions.
And kids do it naturally.
Kids ask more questions than anybody on the planet.
They ask tons.
So we're working on that scale.
Alright.
So go ahead and do a question about the speech.
Something just general about the speech.
Happy.
And general question.
So we're going on to question how, why, where, what, when, do, does, r, is.
D then?
O.
Do Gotcha.
M then e and All sound.
Do Sand.
Felt.
Okay.
You're gonna stop there.
Great.
I n and g.
No sand.
No melting.
You got you're thinking that literal e and the h there.
Okay.
Do melting s then n then o and On on the cut.
W snow.
I'll come back.
Dumelty and snow, m then e and n.
Dumelty and snowman.
Miller star.
G then e n t.
U.
I am talking to William.
Yes.
He get.
Next letter.
A, f then, u then, g n.
I'm scared.
I am I am scared.
I am talking to mom.
F u t.
Let's do a letter.
U r n with ice, we go to e.
K.
I use so as to get a future.
V and.
To get a future it might this is kinda fun.
I'd say to get a future in the Too small.
In the world of water or ice.
Right.
No.
And a future in something else.
Take a deep breath.
Take another one.
That's great.
Take another.
You're doing great.
Tell yourself you're really doing great.
You're doing really well.
Do it again.
You're doing great.
Just take it easy.
Take one more big deep breath.
Be be really good to yourself.
You can change your mind.
One more.
One more big one.
Ready?
Alright.
Do it for read.
I improved ourself.
You do not have to prove yourself.
Okay.
You're doing it.
That's good.
You're good with that.
I'm also just gonna do a on command breathing.
But if you can, it's powerful.
You'll go.
Sorry?
Why not?
Okay.
So now my my turn.
We're gonna ask to be more specific.
Alright.
Yeah.
So I'll good general question.
And you actually didn't become specific about the snowman, so I like that.
I'll ask the question about the snowman.
I would ask the question, why doesn't he have three three balls to make him?
He has one long one here, and it's a small ball.
He has nothing else.
So I'm wondering why.
Hey.
Your question.
Let's ask a question about this tree right there.
What question would you ask about it that you need more information?
Do it, honey.
Just relax.
No.
Dishes are creative or more scientific either way.
Incorrect.
Uh-huh.
And question is?
Okay.
You you got it.
Yeah.
You got it.
So you're gonna ask a question.
Uh-huh.
How about one where y mhmm.
Z.
Now ready.
Mhmm.
Period.
Now ready.
K.
Now ready to go for it.
Period.
And You're gonna scream at the world now.
No.
Question is about the street.
Any questions?
No.
There you are.
The n o.
No.
And h then o.
Then with ice.
Is that of hot.
H o then with rice.
No.
T.
How?
I.
And how in?
Not.
No.
I do not.
How in Sand.
Comes Sand.
Careful.
T.
Next letter.
Careful.
H and e.
How in the truffle?
You're doing great, hon.
How in the I Can I throw all the on the ground?
No.
You gotta go pick that up?
It's broken.
This one's broken up, Frank.
Thanks so much.
Alright.
Honey, you can do it.
Just take a deep breath.
One more deep breath.
One more.
Okay.
Now relax.
Nobody's judging you.
Oh, you can do it.
You can do it, honey.
Good job.
Yeah.
Can do it.
Good job.
I feel better.
Good breathing.
Alright.
How in the w next?
No.
Right here.
How in the w then o then sine and r then l l I and you got sine.
You can do it.
You're so smart.
Want an r based s.
S r z after.
Over the s, there's an ace.
Come on, honey.
Take a look.
O r then l n with your eyes.
Gotta move your eyes out.
Honey, come on.
You can do it.
W o r then l n.
Proof yourself.
Open your eyes up so you can keep spelling.
Then d, then I, and s.
How in the world is Wah.
Go ahead.
Wah.
Close.
And Close out.
Then d.
Mhmm.
Come on, honey.
Come back.