I'm a show.
And if you need to, you can put that on the type of body, that helps you.
Okay.
So Okay.
So we're gonna do something with picture reading because this can be you can think about pictures.
It can unscramble that and distract us some.
Alright.
Would you like to look at ten apps.
These are Christmas y photos.
So if you're like, I don't do Christmas, then take this one.
This is more.
You know, it's Christmas there.
These two are Santa in them.
So do you have a picture you'd like to look at?
I don't know if you're a big celebrator Christmas or not.
Xmas.
Yeah.
I know you're not religious.
Aren't you?
Express.
K.
Do wanna do this one?
This one?
Or this this is one, two, or three?
Which one would you like to do?
You're gonna do three.
Okay.
So this one.
So this is only a Christmas scene because of oh, I guess it's a couple aspects, but it doesn't really Mhmm.
It's more of a winter scene than Christmas scene, so it's so it's nice that way.
So let's start with We do open presents at Christmas.
Open presents.
Okay.
So you still celebrate Christmas.
You're just personally not a believer in God.
That's it's fascinating to me.
And I hate to do that.
Are you guys religious at all of the family or just Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
So you're just Everything.
You're you're you're the one who's saying not just your frontage?
Okay.
So here we go.
Let's take a look at this right here.
The first task is gonna sound simple because you could ask them, do y'all do this?
But the goal is just to work on you being able to scan with more ease.
Okay?
And then start noticing other details.
Even I benefit this activity, even though I can scan the environment, I benefit this activity too.
So it's something we can all work on.
So the identification is due to working on scanning also what you're seeing.
So I am noticing, first off, is this dog here.
K?
What are you gonna see in this picture here?
Oh, how long was my x?
G then, I and n.
Oh, it's just G, I then, s r and l.
So square that.
G lift, I lift, bar max, l.
And just kinda make sure you pull back a little bit more, and that will help.
Let's go to assess, actually.
So you have a drill.
Yes.
I did a couple of drills in there.
Let me mix it all back.
K.
I am noticing the string Uh-huh.
Going through.
What are you noticing?
You're noticing a Uh-huh.
Push it through.
H then o and m then fix that.
Try that now.
It's okay.
It's six.
E.
Home.
Good.
So now Hearts.
K.
I am able to see these two robins.
They're curious to me.
These birds.
K.
What do you wanna sing?
For your dad's video, he should know what you're looking at.
K.
You're noticing?
The Context.
Context and the what?
No.
Go for it.
Look right here.
What do you see?
No.
You're noticing the m then o then n.
The moon.
Can you do two double taps on that moon?
Yeah.
The moon's a full moon.
That is pretty bright.
I actually love it when I come home from my workshop.
In the evening, I fly home, and it is snowing outside or snowed.
Not snowing, but snowed.
I like to walk out at midnight because it's, like, bright.
So it's because the reflection of the moon on the the snow base at bright.
So it's still dark outside, but you can see everything.
It's just really peaceful because everyone's sleeping while you're there.
So it's kinda it's kind of a cool time.
So this is a scene that we can see.
It's kind of more of a nighttime zoom scene due to the fact that you have this moon up, sort of evening z.
For blustering pain.
K.
But not better than I because you have Lysol in the house.
So k.
What else?
I was noticing other things too.
We're noticing what?
V then, o n y as in boy for short.
K.
Number of boys.
Sometimes it's hard to see exactly which gender they are.
K.
I am noticing that The the lights on the tree, which is what one of the things that lets you know that this is a Christmas Eve.
Yeah.
So what else do you see?
You see a s then with your ice cube then u.
S q u.
Ice cream and.
A then r then e squall over.
So you got a square.
Can you point out I guess that's just squares.
Mean, see?
I am noticing the light over here in the bushes.
I'm wondering why it's there.
It's it's a lamppost or something else.
Alright.
K.
So it kinda looks from different things.
Oh, see.
Yeah.
But now that's It's very cozy.
Good point.
To kinda warn you a bit more.
Let's go ahead and spell the word snow.
Don't S n then o n w.
Spell major?
W next, I n t e and r.
Child.
Forest.
Forest, f o r e s n t.
Nice and done.
K.
So forest.
So doing a sentences here.
Let's use the word dog.
And if you're saying winter, let's do winter in a sentence.
Winchar.
From this c.
Did she have w I n t e r, winter.
Next word.
Winter, move your eyes.
V then s r then move your eyes.
So v then r, the word.
I and n, then move your eyes.
It'll be m s and with a g there.
So it'll be s there.
Right?
Did you want the word brings?
Okay.
Yes.
I did or no?
Winter brings.
It's really clean.
Winter brings s next, m next, careful, a, and l brings small.
And the two l's.
Small reaching out.
I and n.
I and, move your eyes, c h then e and s.
Inches.
One hour.
Winter brings small inches.
Go ahead.
O.
Move your eyes.
Gonna go all the way there.
Do what makes sense.
Of.
So let's practice the o to the x so that's not having a g in it.
K.
F r.
O, reach across.
F of s then I.
Okay.
N o, n with your ice, shift w.
Small inches of snow.
March.
Wanna see it?
Let me get that that dog in there.
Zipper.
Bring small inches of snow.
C and Zipper.
Reaching out.
D then o.
Zip.
Zip first.
Mhmm.
G Zip.
Into the snows to dogs.
Great.
Nice.
K.
Good breathing, honey.
Very good.
Yes.
Go ahead and calm yourself down with that.
Zippers.
Okay.
We got dogs.
Zippers.
Now let's go ahead and do the words zippers.
Home and lights in sentence.
Zebras, zip zippers.
You can all zip your coat if you need to.
It's a little bit chilly, though, I think, in this office.
K.
Home and lights.
Get those in a sentence.
There.
You wanted to.
Zebras, zip zippers.
C, move your eyes.
A, move your eyes.
N.
Can.
Q and.
Pardon it.
Open your eyes.
U.
Q u I then e and t.
Can you see quiet?
Superse.
Quiet.
Get quiet.
S then m.
Move your eyes out of the vowel.
A l l.
And quiet, It should hit that l twice as I'm kinda shifting off it.
And quiet, small.
H next.
O next.
H o m next.
E next.
S.
I have white small homes.
More spelled.
Almost spelled.
Good.
H.
Next.
Move your eyes.
Eyes.
H.
Good.
I see that.
H and what?
A and b.
Don't say don't will.
Have m o r.
Just e.
Have more.
Good.
Then q and u.
And quite small homes have more q u.
Okay.
I e t.
You're making it work, which is okay for these sentences.
And small homes the price of homes have more quiet.
You gotta get that letter in.
L good, I good, g h d s.
They have lights, more quiet lights.
We're into question one.
That works.
K.
Now let's put the word mood in this picture into a sentence.
And then we're gonna take a break from the picture for a second and do this skill workout that can help you at home.
K.
With the word mood in it, you can say h o m.
E e.
He's got that j all the way up there.
Home I s is next letter?
U, move your eyes.
People.
N.
For umpire.
Is u n then move your eyes.
Try again.
I or d.
D then e and r.
Home is under t.
Good.
Keep your hand moving.
And then t.
You gotta shift your eyes.
It's under t, then h and e, the these are some soft thoughts that are in your mind that's hard to stay focused.
It's under the After lunch, after spelling.
I tried m o and o then and home is under the moon.
I like that.
So that's what's happening there.
After spelling, we'll go to home to a home store.
Right?
Raise your hand.
Put it out there.
Give everybody this and grab some tape out.
So Here we go.
What we're gonna do is go like this.
Beautiful problem.
I'm gonna cover up some of these rows.
The budget of this is we're just gonna work on making words.
So it builds your skills with your eye movement on the letter board.
It's open ended, but there's no the only thing you gotta do is is one, make words, a meaning word, and two, use at least one letter on top and one on the bottom to work on stretching up and down.
K?
So with people who can do this this skill, so we're gonna take turns.
My turn.
So for instance, you can't spell bad because bad's only on this road, or you can't spell rust because only down here.
You have to fix them.
So I can start with b r, put it down there, a b e.
So I'm gonna be brave.
K?
Your turn.
Spell the word using both rows.
C r e and s t, crest.
Cool.
R e s t, rest.
U-turn.
C then what's that?
C then move your eyes.
A and r, car.
C a r t s, carts.
Alright.
Clear your turn.
I'll spell.
S and p e y, spay.
S p e, spay.
They they figure that.
You got you got you can do something with that.
Do the s p e.
S p p e then a and d.
What are you missing?
Yes.
It's gonna be s and find it.
P r.
There we go.
E then shout.
Right.
Almost there.
A and d.
Spread.
Good.
My turn.
I'm gonna do the words w a s was.
Your turn.
A then.
Come come to it.
R.
Come to it.
T.
Okay.
There we go.
Art.
My turn.
T e a t.
Your turn.
Thank.
A then.
R and?
E r.
Good.
My turn.
Let's do s t a r t s starts.
Your turn.
B e s t.
Best.
My turn.
P e s t.
Best.
Your turn.
R e s t.
I got rest sadly.
Already did.
P r e s and it.
Press it twice.
Press.
My turn.
D r e w, Drew.
Your turn.
V.
That works.
V e r y, very.
Your terms there's hundreds of words there, so we're only going to over so long.
Okay.
R then?
Yep.
Okay.
Then?
And p.
RAP.
There you go.
S t r.
Let's see.
A b.
Strong.
Ow.
You'll turn.
T then.
R then.
Up top.
A and b.
Jump.
Okay.
That's good enough.
This could be a way to work with your skill, and then, like, maybe tomorrow with your dad or Ali, you can do this.
And then you do this side.
Or you could do this one.
Or you could do this roll cover and that roll cover or something.
So you can cover up different letters and find different combinations to build that open ended without there being any pressure just to make sure it's an actual word and you're in good shape.
So good work.
Well done.
Now we go on back to our picture.
There.
First.
So now we're gonna ask questions.
General and specific.
Why we're working on this question asking is because when you are advocating for yourself in society and the environment, it's important that you're able to know what to ask of the information you need.
So if you go to a doctor, your dad or mom may be able to ask good questions, but what if you have one?
Or if you're having a certain need that you haven't been able to express very well, knowing a question, you could ask how do you get that need met.
So so then you also creativity is for permission.
People who I'm prince.
First ask questions.
Okay.
I'm the about the speech.
Something that's general about the speech.
Mhmm.
Happy and general question.
So we're going on to question how, why, where, what, when, do, does, r, s, d then, o.
Do Buncher.
M then e and All stem.
Do Sand.
Okay.
You're getting stuck there.
Great.
I, n, and g.
No sand.
No melting.
You got you're thinking that literal e and the h there.
Okay.
Do melting s then n then o and Uncut.
W snow.
I'll come back.
Demelting snow, m then e n t.
Demelting snow, med.
Muller star.
G then e n t.
U.
I am talking to Lola.
Yes.
You get.
Next letter.
A f then u then t and I'm scared.
I am I am scared.
I am talking to a woman.
F u t Okay.
Let's do a louder.
U r n with your eyes, go to e.
K.
I know.
So it's to get a future.
The end.
To get a future it might this is gonna happen.
I say to get a future in the Too small.
In the world of water or ice.
But No.
And the future is something else.
Take a deep breath.
Take another one.
That's great.
Take another.
You're doing great.
Tell yourself you're really doing great.
You're doing really well.
Do it again.
You're doing great.
Just take it easy.
Take one more big deep breath.
Be be really good to yourself.
You can change your mind.
One more.
One more big one.
Ready?
Alright.
Do it for read.
I improved yourself.
You do not have to improve yourself.
Okay.
You're doing it.
That's good.
You're good with that.
I'm also just gonna do an on command breathing.
But if you can, start.
Okay.
Important.
You'll go.
Sorry?
Why not?
Okay.
So now my question my turn.
We're gonna ask to be more specific.
Alright.
You'll do all good general question, and you to make it.
He has one long one here and it's a small small.
He has one of those.
So I'm wondering why.
K.
Your question.
Let's ask a question about this tree right there.
What question would you ask about it that you need more information do it, honey.
Just relax.
No.
Tissues are creative or more scientific either way.
Mhmm.
Z.
Now ready.
Mhmm.
Period.
Now go ahead.
K.
Now ready.
Go for it.
Period.
And You're gonna scream at the world now.
No.
The question is about the stream.
Any questions?
No.
There you are.
The n o.
No.
And h then o.
Then with rice instead of hot.
H o.
Then with rice.
No.
T.
How?
I and How?
In.
Not.
No.
I do not.
How in Sand.
In comes Sand.
T.
Next letter.
Careful.
H and e.
How in the?
Truffle.
You're doing great, hon.
Out in the I Can throw all the on the ground?
No.
You gotta hook that up?
It's broken.
It's This one's broken up, Frank.
Thanks so much.
Alright.
Honey, you can do it.
Just take a deep breath.
One more deep breath.
One more.
Okay.
Now relax.
Nobody's judging you.
Acting when he got anxious too.
He do it in acting form.
He was even louder and more dramatic.
Okay.
Come on, honey.
You can do it.
Can I hop back in your chair?
You can do it, honey.
Okay.
I'll use it right there.
Just sit right there.
I'll come over by you.
Oh, can do it.
You can do it, honey.
Good job.
You can do it.
I feel better.
Good breathing.
Alright.
How in the w next?
No.
How in the w then r then l, and with your eyes.
Gonna prove yourself.
Honey, come on.
You can do it.
W o r then l and prove yourself.
Open your eyes up so you can keep spelling.
Then Come on, honey.
Come back.